Guide to the Graphic Communications International Union, Local 767M Records 1908-2009
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- Graphic Communications International Union, Local 767M Records, 1908-2009; 5644-001; 15.38 cubic feet 16 boxes
  - OFFICE FILES, 1908-2001; SERIES VI
    Series VI documents the day-to-day procedures at the offices of various local unions, as well as the subjects that were of interest to the union leaders. This series includes information on membership as well as training programs pertinent to the union.
    The series is divided by function: Subseries A: Membership Files, 1908-1967, 1979-1996; Subseries B: Graphic Communications International Union Local 262-C Elections, 1983-1999; Subseries C: Newspapers, 1963-2001; Subseries D: Training, circa 1950s, 1965-1969, 1999. Membership files are arranged chronologically within the subseries. Subseries D: Training is divided by function and arranged chronologically: Part 1: Technical Education Correspondence Courses, circa 1950s; Part 2: Newspaper Manning-Types of Presses [Book], 1965-1969; Part 3: City of Seattle Apprenticeship Program, 1990; Part 4: American Envelope Safety Procedure Proposal, 1992; Part 5: Scott’s Green Book, undated.
    - Membership Files, 1908-1967; 1979-1996; Subseries A
      - Membership Book for Seattle Web Pressmen's Union No. 26, 1908-1967 (Box 15)
      - Monthly Meeting Register of the Graphic Arts International Union Portland Local 90B, 1979-1996 (Box-folder 1/12)
      - Graphic Communications International Union New Member Book, circa 1980s (Box-folder 6/25)
    - Elections, circa 1900s-1960s; 1983-1999; Subseries B
      - Artifact: Wooden voting box, circa 1900s-1960s (Box 14)
      - Graphic Communications International Union Local 262-C Elections, 1983-1999; Subseries B (Box-folder 6/24)
    - Newspapers, 1963-2001; Subseries C
      - Seattle Post-Intelligencer - 100th Anniversary Edition, April 7, 1963 (Box-folder 16/1)
      - Seattle Post-Intelligencer - "P-I to roll off Times press starting tonight", May 22, 1983 (Box-folder 16/2)
      - Seattle Post-Intelligencer - "It's a new P-I but the same old flair", May 23, 1983 (Box-folder 16/3)
      - The Seattle Times - "War Begins", January 16, 1991 (Box-folder 16/4)
      - The Herald - 100th Anniversary Edition, February 11, 2001 (Box-folder 16/5)
    - Training, undated; circa 1950s; 1965-1969; 1990; Subseries D
      - Part 1: Technical Education Correspondence Courses, circa 1950s
        - Correspondence Course Procedures, circa 1950s (Box-folder 6/48)
        - Newspaper Apprentice Pressman Correspondence Course [First to Sixteenth Quarters], circa 1950s (Box-folder 6/49)
        - Technical education Correspondence Course-Bindery Training [Lessons 1-12], circa 1950s (Box-folder 6/50)
        - Technical education Correspondence Course-Offset Process [Lessons 1-11], circa 1950s (Box-folder 6/51)
        - Technical education Correspondence Course-Offset Process [Questions & Answers], circa 1950s (Box-folder 6/52)
        - Technical education Correspondence Course-Offset Process & Web Offset [Review Questions], circa 1950s (Box-folder 6/53)
        - Technical education Correspondence Course-Offset Preparatory [Questions & Answers], circa 1950s (Box-folder 6/54)
        - Technical education Correspondence Course-Offset Preparatory [Lesson 15 & 16 Review], circa 1950s (Box-folder 6/55)
      - Part 2: Newspaper Manning-Types of Presses [Book], 1965-1969 (Box-folder 12/10)
      - Part 3: City of Seattle Apprenticeship Program, 1990 (Box-folder 10/16)
      - Part 4: American Envelope Safety Procedure Proposal, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 11/16)
      - Part 5: Scott’s Green Book, undated (Box-folder 6/47)
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1916-1985; 2001; SERIES VII
    Series VII contains various financial records, which almost entirely originated with Seattle Web Pressmen’s Union No. 26. The series offers insight into the day-to-day financial intake and spending of the union.
    The series is subdivided by format: Subseries A: Cash Books for Seattle Web Pressmen's Union No. 26, 1916-1985; Subseries B: Special Account for Pensioners for Seattle Web Pressmen's Union No. 26, 1965-1977; Subseries C: Financial Records; Subseries D: U.S. Office Products Bankruptcy. Within each subseries, files are arranged chronologically.
    - Cash Books for Seattle Web Pressmen's Union No. 26, 1916-1985; Subseries A
      - Cash Book Local No. 26, 1916-1924 (Box-folder 2/6)
      - Cash Book Local No. 26, 1924-1938 (Box-folder 2/7)
      - Cash Book Local No. 26, 1938-1954 (Box-folder 2/8)
      - Cash Book, 1955-1976 (Box-folder 3/2)
      - Cash Book, 1977-1985 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Special Account for Pensioners for Seattle Web Pressmen's Union No. 26, 1965-1977; Subseries B
      - Special Account for Pensioners, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 1/13)
      - Special Account for Pensioners, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Financial Records, 1934-1935; Subseries C
      - Part 1: Star, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 3/5)
      - Part 2: P.I. Chapel Web Pressmen's Union No. 26, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - U.S. Office Products Bankruptcy, 2001; Subseries D (Box-folder 7/42)
  - BENEFITS, 1990-2003; SERIES VIII
    Series VIII contains several files related to the medical and financial benefits associated with various union/employer contracts. Benefit documents that are mixed in with the Contract/Contract Negotiation files (Series II) are not included in this Series.
    Files are arranged chronologically.
    - American Envelope Changes in Employee Medical/Dental Benefits, 1992 (Box-folder 11/15)
    - American Envelope Company Substance Abuse Policy, 1990 (Box-folder 11/12)
    - Crown Cork & Seal Company, Inc./292-M, 1994 (Box-folder 12/14)
    - Eagle Paper Box Profit Sharing Plan and Trust / Medical, 1990-1997 (Box-folder 6/21)
    - Mail-Well Corporation Benefit Plans, 1984; 1994-1997 (Box-folder 11/13-14)
    - Mail-Well Corporation Benefit Plans/Conduct and Ethics Code, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 11/17)
    - Q-Media Services (Fife, Washington) Plant Closing And Medical Insurance, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 9/13)
- Graphic Communications International Union, Local 767M records, 1894-2011; 1970-2000; 5644-002; 75.85 cubic feet (70 boxes)
  Open to all users.
  Brian Earl, President GCIU 767M, null
  - 25th Anniversary Souvenir Book/Photoengravers Union 1, 1894-1919 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - 75 Years of Lithographers Books, 1957 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Cash Book, 1956-1991 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - IPU #26 Cash Book, 1919-1934 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Star Chapel 2% Relief Assistance Book, 1932-1934; undated (Box-folder 1/5-7)
  - Minutes of the Bindery Woman's Union N113, 1902-1907 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - New Century Dictionary Vol.1-3, 1927 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Pictures, 1911-1917 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - 1st New Years Banquet Menu/Photengravers, 1912 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - The American Photoengraver, 1910-1917 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - 15th Annual Convention International Photoengravers Union on N.A., 1914 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Plate Makers Criterion, 1910 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Seattle Times 1970s, 1980s, 1990s -Part 1, circa 1970-1999 (Box 2)
  - Seattle Times 1970s, 1980s, 1990s -Part 2, circa 1970-1999 (Box 3)
  - Seattle Times Carriers - Part 1 (Box 3)
  - Seattle Times Carriers - Part 2 (Box 4)
  - Bylaws etc. - Part 1 (Box 4)
  - Various old Contracts Miscellaneous Pre 1990s - Part 3 (Box 5)
  - Bylaws etc. - Part 2 (Box 5)
    begins after "ILPF Minutes"
  - Contracts UW 1970s-1980s - Part 1, circa 1970-1989 (Box 6)
  - Contracts UW 1970s-1980s - Part 2, circa 1970-1989 (Box 7)
  - Various old Contracts Miscellaneous Pre 1990s - Part 1 (Box 7)
  - Various old Contracts Miscellaneous Pre 1990 - Part 2 (Box 8)
  - GAC - Part 1 (Box 9)
  - GAC - Part 2 (Box 10)
  - Minutes, Seminars, Negociations -Part 1 (Box 10)
  - Minutes, seminars, Negociations -Part 2 (Box 11)
  - Contracts: GAC contracts, GAC grievances, Old Bylaws - Part 1, circa 1983-2002 (Box 11)
  - Contracts: GAC contracts, GAC grievances, Old Bylaws - Part 2, circa 1983-2002 (Box 12)
  - Contracts: GAC contracts, GAC grievances, Old Bylaws - Part 3, circa 1983-2002 (Box 13)
  - Old Contract Files: State of Washington Printing Olympia, Everett Herald, Color Control, Lawton Printing Litho - Part 1, circa 1938-1997 (Box 13)
  - Old Contract Files: State of Washington Printing Olympia, Everett Herald, Color Control, Lawton Printing Litho - Part 2, circa 1938-1997 (Box 14)
  - Seattle Times Bargaining Notes - Part 1, 1996-1998 (Box 15)
  - Seattle Times Bargaining Notes - Part 2, 1996-1998 (Box 16)
  - Ken Kennedy Grievance "From Steven's Office" - Part 1 (Box 17)
  - Ken Kennedy Grievance "From Steven's Office" - Part 2 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Negotiations, Contracts, etc. - Part 1 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Negotiations, Contracts, etc. - Part 2 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, Negotiations, Contracts, etc. -Part 3 (Box 20)
    first four folders
  - "Brian PDX 292" - Part 1 (Box 20)
  - "Brian PDX 292" - Part 2 (Box 21)
  - "Brian" Other Locals - Part 1 (Box 21)
  - "Brian" Other Locals - Part 2 (Box 22)
  - "Brian" Other Locals -Part 3 (Box 23)
  - "Brian" Negotiations, Executive Board, Appeals - Part 1 (Box 23)
    After "Portland 1976 Local 202"
  - "Brian" Negotiations, Executive Board, Appeals - Part 2 (Box 24)
  - "Brian" Local 292 and Other Locals (Box 25)
  - 1999 Election, Seattle Times, Taxes, Bank Statements…etc. - Part 1, circa 1999 (Box 25)
  - 1999 Election, Seattle Times, Taxes, Bank Statements…etc. - Part 2, circa 1999 (Box 26)
  - Benefits Agreements, Conference materials, Plans, Election ephemera - Part 1 (Box 26)
    After "GCIU National Health Care…"
  - Benefits Agreements, Conference materials, Plans, Election ephemera - Part 2 (Box 27)
  - "For Brian Earl, Sekardi 2001" Contracts, Negotiations, Correspondence - Part 1, circa 2001 (Box 27)
    Begins with ABC documents
  - "For Brian Earl, Sekardi 2001" Contracts, Negotiations, Correspondence - Part 2, circa 2001 (Box 28)
  - Medical, Dental Healthcare, Grievances, Terminations - Part 1, circa 1998-2007 (Box 28)
  - Medical, Dental Healthcare, Grievances, Terminations - Part 2, circa 1998-2007 (Box 29)
  - Proposals, Agreements, Items in tabbed-dividers -Part 1, circa 1990-2000 (Box 29)
    Begins after folder titled "October 1998 Nominations…"
  - Proposals, Agreements, Items in tabbed-dividers -Part 2, circa 1990-2000 (Box 30)
    first 3 folders in box
  - Allied Printing, Certificates, Brochures, Binders, 1920s-1940s label books, floppy disks, contains container list, circa 1920-2007 (Box 30)
  - Lawton Printing, Nu-Way, Lasting Impressions, King County Print Shop - Part 1, circa 1977-1997 (Box 31)
  - Lawton Printing, Nu-Way, Lasting Impressions, King County Print Shop - Part 2, circa 1977-1997 (Box 32)
  - FY, Geographics, DOL Forms etc… - Part 1, circa 1996-2002 (Box 32)
  - FY, Geographics, DOL Forms etc… - Part 2, circa 1996-2002 (Box 33)
  - Conventions, Conferences, Elections, Shop Steward Training, Financial Reports, Teamster Merger, circa 1991-2012 (Box 34)
  - Bridgetown, Ethographics, GAC, Columbia Litho, Everett Herald - Part 1, circa 1962-2003 (Box 35)
  - Bridgetown, Ethographics, GAC, Columbia Litho, Everett Herald - Part 2, circa 1962-2003 (Box 36)
  - "Portland, OR Merger Local 292" - Part 1, circa 1982 (Box 36)
  - "Portland, OR Merger Local 292" - Part 2, circa 1982 (Box 37)
  - "Closed Shops: ACC, Creative Printing, Island Graphics, The Olympian" - Part 1, circa 1997-2011 (Box 37)
  - Closed Shops: ACC, Creative Printing, Island Graphics, The Olympian - Part 2, circa 1997-2011 (Box 38)
  - Closed Shops: Say it on Anything, Vyper Sportswear, All Color Printing, Direct Mail, Tuff T's Screen Printing, Press Craft, A & B Printing, Rainier Embroidery, Diamond Press, A & L Printing, Lincoln and Allen - Part 1, 1998-2011 (Box 38)
  - Technical Education Correspondence Course (Item list in first folder) (Box 39)
  - Merger with Local 262C, Old Closed Shops: Oregon Catholic Press 1992, Lane Miles 1992, Lincoln and Allen 1992, Hicks Chatten 1992, circa 1992 (Box 39)
  - Conference Materials, Interlocal Correspondence, COLA, Consumer Price Index - Part 1 (Box 40)
  - Conference Materials, Interlocal Correspondence, COLA, Consumer Price Index - Part 2 (Box 41)
  - Conference Materials, Interlocal Correspondence, COLA, Consumer Price Index - Part 3 (Box 42)
  - State Department Contracts, Olympia State Printing Plant, V/N Graphics - Part 1, circa 1986-2003 (Box 42)
  - State Department Contracts, Olympia State Printing Plant, V/N Graphics - Part 2, circa 1986-2003 (Box 43)
  - GCIU Independent Auditers Report, Pre Press MAC classes, Training, Education - Part 1 -, circa 1993-2003 (Box 43)
  - GCIU Independent Auditers Report, Pre Press MAC classes, Training, Education - Part 2, circa 1993-2003 (Box 44)
  - Azpitarte, Graphics and Printing Industry Dental Trust, Times Pressman, Tom Forrey… etc. - Part 1, circa 1986-1999 (Box 44)
  - Azpitarte, Graphics and Printing Industry Dental Trust, Times Pressman, Tom Forrey… etc. - Part 2, circa 1986-1999 (Box 45)
  - Insurance Information, Educational Fund Bond, Local 11, Retirement…etc. - Part 1-, circa 1985 (Box 45)
  - Insurance Information, Educational Fund Bond, Local 11, Retirement…etc. - Part 2, circa 1985 (Box 46)
  - Shop Stewards, Conference Materials, Scrapbook etc. - Part 1, circa 1995-2008 (Box 46)
  - Shop Stewards, Conference Materials, Scrapbook, etc. - Part 2, circa 1995-2008 (Box 47)
  - Auditors Reports 2005-2008, Merger Agreement 1963, Board Minutes 2005, Withdrawls, Expulsions - Part 1, circa 1963-2008 (Box 47)
  - "IBT Conventions", DVD, - Part 1, circa 2006-2011 (Box 47)
  - "IBT Conventions" - Part 2, circa 2006-2011 (Box 48)
  - Johnson Cox, Everett Herald, Lawton Printing, Kirkland Tattoo, and The Sun Contracts and Negotiations - Part 1 - (begins after IBT 2011 materials), circa 1990-2000 (Box 48)
  - Johnson Cox, Everett Herald, Lawton Printing, Kirkland Tattoo, and The Sun Contracts and Negotiations - Part 2, circa 1990-2000 (Box 49)
  - Seattle Times, North American Newspaper Conference, Independent Auditors Repor (begins with "Pressman" newspaper), circa 1995-2000 (Box 49)
  - Executive Board Minutes 1955-1986; Special General Board Minutes 2004, Donald A. Kushmaul, Auditors Reports 1998 - Part 1, circa 1955-2004 (Box 50)
  - Executive Board Minutes 1955-1986; Special General Board Minutes 2004, Donald A. Kushmaul, Auditors Reports 1998 - Part 2, circa 1955-2004 (Box 51)
    first two folders of "minutes"
  - "Trojan Contracts Late 80s- Early 90s", circa 1980-1995 (Box 51)
  - GAC documents, circa 1998-2005 (Box 52)
  - Various organizing materials and contracts, circa 1990-2000 (Box 52)
  - "GCIU Archives", circa 1986-1999 (Box 53)
    begins with "Graphic Communicator" newspapers
  - "Portland Oregon Merger 292", circa 1985-1999 (Box 54)
  - Executive Board related documents 1998-1999, WSLC reports, directory, circa 1998-2000 (Box 54)
  - Local 202 GAC Standard Contract pamphlets, National Labor Relations Act Pamphlet, Convention Pamphlets, 1973-1988 (Box 54)
  - Agreement pamphlets, Constitutions and By Laws Pamphlets, Workers Right's Information Pamphlets, Directories, IBT Conference Proceedings - Part 1, circa 1910-2011 (Box 55)
  - Agreement pamphlets, Constitutions and By Laws Pamphlets, Workers Right's Information pamphlets, directories, IBT Conference Proceedings - Part 2 - cassette tapes, 1910-2010 (Box 56)
  - University of Washington, P.E.R.C, Seattle Times, Oregon Engraving and Rubber Plates, Overnight Printing, Everett Herald, circa 1996-2001 (Box 57)
  - Englehardt Merger, City of Seattle, Seattle Times, Overnight Printing, Spokesman Review, Pride Printing, circa 1991-2002 (Box 58)
  - Papermill Printing, Grievances, Negotiations with Renick Litho, Pride Printing, circa 1989-2001 (Box 59)
  - Grievances, Everett Herald, North American Newspaper Conference, Other Convention Materials, Ergonomics WISHA, circa 1984-2003 (Box 60)
  - Arbitrations, Apprenticeship Programs, North American Newspaper Conference, 2006 Teamsters Conference, circa 1988-206 (Box 61)
  - Seattle Times, Trojan Litho, Tacoma News Tribune, Color Control, circa 1990-2005 (Box 62)
  - Color Control, Trojan, News Tribune, circa 1989-2002 (Box 63)
  - Color Control, Trojan, circa 1989-2002 (Box 64)
  - Legal sized items, realia, safe deposit box, large ledgers (Box 65)
  - Large seal (Box 66)
  - Seals, cassette tapes (Box 67)
  - Seals, buttons and patches, printing "bugs" (Box 68)
  - Posters, photographs, certificates, flag, wall hanging (Box 69)
  - Tube of Posters (Box 70)